## WILLEM N. ELSDON

✓ willelsdon@gmail.com

**4** 909-202-3855

in willem-elsdon

• welsdon

Poise, Idaho

Summary: A highly motivated systems engineer with an **active TS/SCI** clearance and over three years of experience in mechanical design, systems engineering, and software quality assurance. My goal is to join a rewarding and collarborative team where I can implement my diverse set of skills to use in a renowned company such as High Point Aerotechnologies.

## Professional Experience

## Raytheon Intelligence & Space — Systems Engineer II IV&T — SEIT

February 2022 - Present

- Lead daily Scrums via **Jira** with the IV&T team and brainstorm solutions to story blockers with leadership
- Create new feature files used in automation, leveraging Gherkin syntax and Visual Studio Code via VDIs
- Verify Discrepancy Reports (DR's) from creation to final integration, review pull requests using BitBucket
- Assist coordinating test plans and events for Integrated Master Schedule (IMS) milestones using Jira and Confluence
- Frequently travel to sites to help integrate the FORGE system, requires extensive cross-product collaboration
  Systems Engineering SEIT
- Spearheaded an initiative to overhaul and polish the MBSE model of the FORGE system while adhering to SysML
- Worked with SMEs from all product teams to better structure and organize the model, ensuring a scalable and future proof representation of the system that adheres to **DoDAF** architecture
- Developed scripts (Apache VTL) for use with CAMEO that captures necessary information for customer facing documentation
- Led various customer meetings (Technical Exchange Meetings, **TEMs**), verifying requirements were met and appropriate actions were in place to meet the demands of those slated for completion

# Raytheon Intelligence & Space — Systems Engineer I IV&T — SEIT

July 2020 - February 2022

- Performed various tests (integration, regression, performance/SOAKs) throughout the system
- Wrote technical documentation (Test Cases, Integration Cases, Test Procedures) for new capabilities added to a legacy program, making sure to adhere to the requirements outlined in **DOORS**
- Participated in customer facing test events for requirement verification (ran, collected, and verified results)
- Brought new and updated documentation through review (review boards & critical review meetings)
- Troubleshot and documented all encountered issues using ClearQuest and root-cause analysis

#### Western Aircraft — Engineering Intern

October 2019 - April 2020

Avionics — Mechanical

- Utilized Solidworks to design tooling used in the repair and maintenance of private aircraft (Pilatus, Beechcraft, Dassault Falcon)
- Helped engineer solutions for the upgrade and repair of avionics, leveraging ANSI drawings that outlined installation and removal
- Communicated with FAA DER's to validate designs, once validated I worked with A&P mechanics throughout installation
- Took accurate physical measurements of aircraft internals to identify ideal mounting and repair locations
- Created drawings for maintenance tools of private aircraft, once the **BOM** was complete, obtained quotes from local companies

### Northrop Grumman — Composites Structure Design Intern Ducts & Doors — Mechanical

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Collaborated with managerial and engineering staff to determine optimal solutions (using CATIA) to repair composite parts damaged during the manufacturing process for the air inlet ducts of the F-35
- · Communicated these repairs directly to Liaison Engineers where they were implemented immediately
- Revised three Material and Process specifications to create a more efficient manufacturing procedure and successfully presented them
- Organized all previous repairs into one catalog, allowing for quicker repair acquisition and less manufacturing downtime

### EDUCATION

#### Mechanical Engineering — Bachelor of Science

May 2020

Boise State University - Boise, Idaho

GPA: 3.7

Gem Scholarship Recipient, SWE Member, ME Club Treasurer, Concrete Canoe

#### Air Quality Lab — Research Assistant

- Utilized Excel, interpreted PM2.5 and PM10 data that was gathered during the summer of 2017 within the Treasure Valley
- Data was collected using state-of-the-art MOUDI II devices which helped analyze solutions to minimizing the production of fine particulate matter, and what could be done as a short term solution
- Presented my findings to Boise State engineering faculty where my paper has since been used as a template for future reports

### SKILLS

CameoEA, Solidworks, Linux, Atlassian, Excel, Scrum Master, Techincal Writing & Communication, Visual Studio Code, SysML,
 Adaptability, Customer Interaction, Troubleshooting, Root Cause Analysis, Log analysis, DOORS, MBSE, Quality Assurance